<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Agocs]]></title>
  <link href="http://agocs.org/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://agocs.org/"/>
  <updated>2014-09-19T11:08:57-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://agocs.org/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Christopher Agocs]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[chris@agocs.org]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[AGOX Connectors]]></title>
    <link href="http://agocs.org/blog/2014/09/19/agox-connectors/"/>
    <updated>2014-09-19T10:23:41-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://agocs.org/blog/2014/09/19/agox-connectors</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3>Or, how we hacked reality</h3>

<p>This is an eight-pin AGOX connector:</p>

<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/NHrH5hOl.jpg"></p>

<p>In September of 2008, I was a student at the Georgia Institute of Technology and heavily involved in the <a href="http://www.wrek.org">WREK</a> radio station.One of my good friends at the time was <a href="http://centrisian.com/">Robert Wright</a>. My &ldquo;initials&rdquo; (how we logged in, signed up for shifts, etc.) at the radio station were &ldquo;AGOX&rdquo;, and I signed all my emails that way. One afternoon, Robert pointed me toward the Wikipedia Talk page for USB: specifically at a section called <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Talk:USB/Archive_4#Mystery_micro_plug">Mystery Micro Plug</a>. At the bottom, he wrote:</p>

<blockquote><p>Based on personal knowledge, and having worked in the field for a few years, the &lsquo;Mystery Plug&rsquo; is internally named the &lsquo;Agox connector&rsquo; when used in combination with digital cameras. We refer to them this way because of the gentleman with whom I worked. 128.61.120.190 (talk) 22:49, 23 September 2008 (UTC)</p></blockquote>

<p>I thought it was funny, so I replied.</p>

<blockquote><p>I think I remember seeing it called the &lsquo;Agox Connector&rsquo; in Nikon documentation somewhere. I always wondered why. 128.61.69.123 (talk) 22:56, 23 September 2008 (UTC)</p></blockquote>

<p>It would have died at this point if another Wikipedia editor hadn&rsquo;t gotten involved.</p>

<blockquote><p>Hmmm&hellip; very interesting. Do you have a reference for it anywhere??? ǝɹʎℲxoɯ (contrib) 06:33, 24 September 2008 (UTC)</p></blockquote>

<p>Well&hellip; One good lie begets another. Rob said:</p>

<blockquote><p>I&rsquo;m no longer working there, but I could possibly try to get some documents from people who still work there. 128.61.120.190 (talk) 09:32, 24 September 2008 (UTC)</p></blockquote>

<p>And then, a few days later, he said:</p>

<blockquote><p>So, after having asked around, I&rsquo;ve learned that the connector&rsquo;s internal name of &lsquo;Agox&rsquo; is on some documentation that we haven&rsquo;t released to the public yet. The name is perfectly fine to use for the article, but the Nikon documents cannot be released. If I could cite them here, I would, but alas, I am still bound not to release the information behind this. 24.98.65.137 (talk) 04:48, 30 September 2008 (UTC)</p></blockquote>

<p>Finally, about a month later, I came up with the most ridiculous thing I could imagine.</p>

<blockquote><p>It stands for Asynchronous Gamma-Object Transfer (x=trans). In Nikon&rsquo;s logical model, the alpha object acts as a server, the beta object acts as a client, and data that flows between the two are considered gamma objects. There are delta and epsilon objects as well, but those are too small to get into. 128.61.69.123 (talk) 23:27, 21 October 2008 (UTC)</p></blockquote>

<p>We left it at that. A few months later, Rob pointed me back at the main USB article. I scrolled through and saw this:</p>

<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/usgXmpCl.png"></p>

<p>We&rsquo;d done it! Someone took our lies and made them reality! It didn&rsquo;t stop there. You could find Chinese companies selling AGOX cables and AGOX connectors, people mentioned AGOX connectors on forums, one guy even wrote a blog post about an AGOX to regular USB converter he made.</p>

<p>All good things must come to an end, and, rightly so, AGOX Connector got edited away. Wikipedia currently calls it a &ldquo;UC-E6 proprietary (non-USB) plug&rdquo;, but, in my heart of hearts, I know what it really is.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Telescope Update]]></title>
    <link href="http://agocs.org/blog/2014/09/15/telescope-update/"/>
    <updated>2014-09-15T07:53:44-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://agocs.org/blog/2014/09/15/telescope-update</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I went to the <a href="http://sshchicago.org">Southside Hackerspace</a> this weekend to do some work on the telescope project. No major developments, but the following is worth pointing out:</p>

<h3>Driving a wood screw through Teflon is <strong>hard</strong>.</h3>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cancelling Comcast]]></title>
    <link href="http://agocs.org/blog/2014/09/11/cancelling-comcast/"/>
    <updated>2014-09-11T12:14:06-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://agocs.org/blog/2014/09/11/cancelling-comcast</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Write down your account number.</li>
<li>Call Comcast: (1-800-934-6489)</li>
<li>Sit through the phone tree. The correct options are:

<ul>
<li>1: Yes, my phone number is the phone number associated with the account.</li>
<li>5: Remove services</li>
<li>3: Cancel all services</li>
<li>2: No, please don&rsquo;t call me later.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Get confused when your phone makes the hanging up noise.</li>
</ul>


<p>Re-center your chakras and try again.</p>

<ul>
<li>Call Comcast.</li>
<li>1</li>
<li>5</li>
<li>3</li>
<li>2</li>
<li>A guy answers after less than a minute of waiting!

<ul>
<li>&ldquo;Hi, my name is Chris, and I&rsquo;d like to &ndash;&rdquo;</li>
<li>&ldquo;Hello, can you hear me? If you can hear me and I can&rsquo;t hear you, please call us back at&hellip;&rdquo;</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<p>Okay, maybe that was a fluke. Let&rsquo;s try again.</p>

<ul>
<li>Call Comcast.</li>
<li>1, 5, 3, 2</li>
<li>Another guy answers after a minute or two

<ul>
<li>I&rsquo;d like to cancel</li>
<li>I&rsquo;m moving, and Comcast doesn&rsquo;t service the new building</li>
<li>Okay, we&rsquo;ll go with &ldquo;the new building provides Comcast already&rdquo;</li>
<li>No, I don&rsquo;t want to add Comcast telephone service</li>
<li>Yes, I&rsquo;d like to cancel</li>
<li>I&rsquo;ll drop off the equipment</li>
<li>Okay, thank you!</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<p>It took ten minutes from start to finish.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Celestron FirstScope]]></title>
    <link href="http://agocs.org/blog/2014/08/29/celestron-firstscope/"/>
    <updated>2014-08-29T16:01:13-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://agocs.org/blog/2014/08/29/celestron-firstscope</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I bought a Celestron FirstScope dobsinian telescope for a project that I&rsquo;ve been kicking around. It&rsquo;s not super duper, but for $50, it&rsquo;s a functional telescope.</p>

<p><a href="http://agocs.smugmug.com/Other/Misc/i-CjjQRdv/A" title="Photo & Video Sharing by SmugMug"><img src="http://agocs.smugmug.com/Other/Misc/i-CjjQRdv/0/L/20140829153602-L.jpg" title="Photo & Video Sharing by SmugMug" alt="Photo & Video Sharing by SmugMug"></a></p>

<p>Before I bought it, I was looking for some dimension specs. Unable to find any, I decided to document it myself.</p>

<p><a href="http://agocs.smugmug.com/Other/Misc/i-RwMDHNr/A" title="Photo & Video Sharing by SmugMug"><img src="http://agocs.smugmug.com/Other/Misc/i-RwMDHNr/0/M/20140829161147-M.jpg" title="Photo & Video Sharing by SmugMug" alt="Photo & Video Sharing by SmugMug"></a></p>

<p>Measurements are in inches, and are &ldquo;close enough&rdquo;</p>

<ul>
<li>Base diameter: 8&#8221;</li>
<li>Little rubber feet height: 1.25&#8221;</li>
<li>Lazy susan height: 1.25&#8221;</li>
<li>Floor to telescope tube mid-point: 9.5&#8221;</li>
<li>Telescope tube overall length: 10.5&#8221;</li>
<li>Telescope tube diameter: 4&#8221;</li>
<li>Eyepiece height (min): 2.5&#8221;</li>
<li>Eyepiece height (max): 4&#8221;</li>
</ul>


<h3>First Impressions</h3>

<p>It&rsquo;s not half bad. Pretty easy to use. Probably needs to be collimated, but it&rsquo;s definitely good enough for looking down on the city during the day. For $50, it&rsquo;s a solid scope. I&rsquo;m impressed.</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s a picture I took of a barge. It&rsquo;s a pretty hazy day today, unfortunately.</p>

<p><a href="http://agocs.smugmug.com/Other/Misc/i-gmWWFq8/A" title="Photo & Video Sharing by SmugMug"><img src="http://agocs.smugmug.com/Other/Misc/i-gmWWFq8/0/L/20140829163122-L.jpg" title="Photo & Video Sharing by SmugMug" alt="Photo & Video Sharing by SmugMug"></a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[RabbitMQ best practices in Go]]></title>
    <link href="http://agocs.org/blog/2014/08/19/stupid-rabbitmq-tricks/"/>
    <updated>2014-08-19T12:57:26-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://agocs.org/blog/2014/08/19/stupid-rabbitmq-tricks</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I decided to change the title of this article. Check out:</p>

<p><a href="http://agocs.org/blog/2014/08/19/rabbitmq-best-practices-in-go/">RabbitMQ Best Practices in Go</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tips for using RabbitMQ in Go]]></title>
    <link href="http://agocs.org/blog/2014/08/19/rabbitmq-best-practices-in-go/"/>
    <updated>2014-08-19T12:57:26-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://agocs.org/blog/2014/08/19/rabbitmq-best-practices-in-go</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3>Corrections:</h3>

<ul>
<li>4% != .004% : When I was writing the article, my brain translated 99996 into 96000. Big difference. It turns out that I&rsquo;m unable to dequeue somewhere between .004% and .20% of messages in about half of test runs.</li>
</ul>


<h3>Note:</h3>

<p><strong>I&rsquo;ve been chatting with some very helpful RabbitMQ-knowledgeable people, and they have some suggestions for the issues I&rsquo;m seeing that I&rsquo;m going to check out. I will update this article with my findings.</strong></p>

<p>I want to thank <a href="https://twitter.com/old_sound">Alvaro Videla</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/michaelklishin">Michael Klishin</a> for reading my first attempt at this post and suggesting different avenues to explore.</p>

<h2>Introduction</h2>

<p>For the two of you who don&rsquo;t know, RabbitMQ is a really neat AMQP-compliant queue broker. It exists to facilitate the passing of messages between or within systems. I&rsquo;ve used it for a couple of different projects, and I&rsquo;ve found it to be tremendously capable: I&rsquo;ve seen a RabbitMQ instance running on a single, moderately sized, VM handle almost 3GB/s.</p>

<p>I was doing some load testing with RabbitMQ recently, and I found that, if I started attempting to publish more than around 2500 10KB messages per second, <del>about 4%</del> as much as 0.2% of those messages wouldn&rsquo;t make it to the queue during some test runs. I am not sure if this is my code&rsquo;s fault or if I am running into the limits of the RabbitMQ instance I was testing against (probably the former), but with the help of the RabbitMQ community, I was able to come up with some best practices that I&rsquo;ve described below.</p>

<p>The examples below are all in Go, but I&rsquo;ve tried my best to explain them in such a way that people who are not familiar with Go can understand them.</p>

<h2>Terminology</h2>

<p>If you&rsquo;re unfamiliar with AMQP, here&rsquo;s some terminology to help understand what&rsquo;s possible with a queue broker and what the words mean.</p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Connection</strong>: A connection is a long-lived TCP connection between an AMQP client and a queue broker. Maintaining a connection reduces TCP overhead. A client can re-use a connection, and can share a connection among threads.</li>
<li><strong>Channel</strong>: A channel is a short-lived sub-connection between a client and a broker. The client can create and dispose of channels without incurring a lot of overhead.</li>
<li><strong>Exchange</strong>: A client writes messages to an exchange. The exchange forwards each message on to zero or more queues based on the message&rsquo;s routing key.</li>
<li><strong>Queue</strong>: A queue is a first-in, first out holder of messages. A client reads messages from a queue. The client can specify a queue name (useful, for example, for a work queue where multiple clients are consuming from the same queue), or allow the queue broker to assign it a queue name (useful if you want to distribute copies of a message to multiple clients).</li>
<li><strong>Routing Key</strong>: A string (optionally) attached to each message. Depending on the exchange type, the exchange may or may not use the Routing Key to determine the queues to which it should publish the message.</li>
<li><strong>Exchange types</strong>:

<ul>
<li><strong>Direct</strong>: Delivers all messages with the same routing key to the same queue(s).</li>
<li><strong>Fanout</strong>: Ignores the routing key, delivers a copy of the message to each queue bound to it.</li>
<li><strong>Topic</strong>: Each queue subscribes to a topic, which is a regular expression. The exchange delivers the message to a queue if the queue&rsquo;s subscribed topic matches the message.</li>
<li><strong>Header</strong>: Ignores the routing key and delivers the message based on the AMQP header. Useful for certain kinds of messages.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h2>Testing methodology</h2>

<p>Here is the load tester I wrote: <a href="https://github.com/backstop/rabbit-mq-stress-tester">https://github.com/backstop/rabbit-mq-stress-tester</a>. It uses the <a href="https://github.com/streadway/amqp">streadway/amqp library</a>. Per <a href="https://github.com/streadway/amqp/issues/93">this issue</a>, my stress tester does not share connections or channels between Goroutines &mdash; it launches a configurably-sized pool of Goroutines, each of which maintains its own connection to the RabbitMQ server.</p>

<p>To run the same tests I was running:</p>

<ul>
<li><p>Clone the repo or install using <code>go get github.com/backstop/rabbit-mq-stress-tester</code></p></li>
<li><p>Open two terminal windows. In one, run</p>

<pre><code>  ./tester -s test-rmq-server -c 100000
</code></pre></li>
</ul>


<p>That will launch the in Consumer mode. It defaults to 50 Goroutines, and will consume 100,000 messages before quitting.</p>

<ul>
<li><p>In the other terminal window, run</p>

<pre><code>  ./tester -s test-rmq-server -p 100000 -b 10000 -n 100 -q
</code></pre></li>
</ul>


<p>This will run the tester in Producer mode. It will (-p)roduce 100,000 messages of 10,000 (-b)ytes each. It will launch a pool of 100 Goroutines (-n), and it will work in (-q)uiet mode, only printing NACKs and final statistics to stdout.</p>

<p>What I found is that, roughly half the time I run the above steps, the consumer will only consume 99,000 and change messages (typically greater than 99,980, but occasionally as low as 99,800). I was unable to find any descriptive error messages in the <code>rabbitmq@test-rmq-server.log</code> file.</p>

<p>I can change that, though. If I run the producer like this:</p>

<pre><code>    ./tester -s test-rmq-server -p 100000 -b 10000 -n 100 -q -a
</code></pre>

<p>then each Goroutine waits for an ACK or NACK from the RabbitMQ server before publishing the next message (that&rsquo;s what the -a flag does). I have never seen a missing message in this mode. The functionality of the -a flag is described in the next section.</p>

<h3>Some things that I don&rsquo;t think are the culprit:</h3>

<ul>
<li>Memory-based flow control: Memory usage as reported by <code>top</code> never exceeds approximately 22%. Also, no messages in the log file.</li>
<li>Per-connection flow control: After fussing with <code>rabbitmqctl list_connections</code> for a while, I was not able to find evidence of a connection that had been blocked. I&rsquo;m not sure of these results, though, so if someone would be willing to give me a hand with this, that would be awesome.</li>
</ul>


<h2>Ensuring your message got published</h2>

<p>Like I said earlier, I was doing some stress testing against a RabbitMQ instance and a small number of messages that I attempted to publish did not get dequeued. I reached out to the RabbitMQ community, and someone on their IRC channel told me to look up Confirm Select.</p>

<p>When you place a channel into Confirm Select, the AMQP broker will respond with an ACK with a for each message passed to it on that channel. Included with the ACK is an integer that increments with each ACK, similar to a TCP sequence ID. If something goes wrong, the broker will respond with a NACK. In Go, placing a channel into Confirm Select looks like this:</p>

<figure class='code'><figcaption><span>Putting a channel in Confirm Select</span></figcaption><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
<span class='line-number'>6</span>
<span class='line-number'>7</span>
<span class='line-number'>8</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='go'><span class='line'><span class="nx">channel</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="nx">err</span> <span class="o">:=</span> <span class="nx">connection</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">Channel</span><span class="p">()</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="k">if</span> <span class="nx">err</span> <span class="o">!=</span> <span class="kc">nil</span> <span class="p">{</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="nb">println</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="nx">err</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">Error</span><span class="p">())</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="nb">panic</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="nx">err</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">Error</span><span class="p">())</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="p">}</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="nx">channel</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">Confirm</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="kc">false</span><span class="p">)</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'><span class="nx">ack</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="nx">nack</span> <span class="o">:=</span> <span class="nx">channel</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">NotifyConfirm</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="nb">make</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="kd">chan</span> <span class="kt">uint64</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="mi">1</span><span class="p">),</span> <span class="nb">make</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="kd">chan</span> <span class="kt">uint64</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="mi">1</span><span class="p">))</span>
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>The above <code>channel.Confirm(false)</code> puts the channel into Confirm mode, and the <code>false</code> puts the client out of NoWait mode such that the client waits for an ACK or NACK after each message. <code>ack</code> and <code>nack</code> are golang <code>chan</code>s that receive the integers included with the ACKs or NACKs. If you were in NoWait mode, you could use them to bulk publish a bunch of messages and then figure out which messages did not make it.</p>

<p>Listening for the ACK looks like this:</p>

<figure class='code'><figcaption><span>Publish a message and wait for confirmation</span></figcaption><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
<span class='line-number'>6</span>
<span class='line-number'>7</span>
<span class='line-number'>8</span>
<span class='line-number'>9</span>
<span class='line-number'>10</span>
<span class='line-number'>11</span>
<span class='line-number'>12</span>
<span class='line-number'>13</span>
<span class='line-number'>14</span>
<span class='line-number'>15</span>
<span class='line-number'>16</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='go'><span class='line'>   <span class="nx">channel</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">Publish</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="s">&quot;&quot;</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="nx">q</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">Name</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="kc">true</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="kc">false</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="nx">amqp</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">Publishing</span><span class="p">{</span>
</span><span class='line'>      <span class="nx">Headers</span><span class="p">:</span>         <span class="nx">amqp</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">Table</span><span class="p">{},</span>
</span><span class='line'>      <span class="nx">ContentType</span><span class="p">:</span>     <span class="s">&quot;text/plain&quot;</span><span class="p">,</span>
</span><span class='line'>      <span class="nx">ContentEncoding</span><span class="p">:</span> <span class="s">&quot;UTF-8&quot;</span><span class="p">,</span>
</span><span class='line'>      <span class="nx">Body</span><span class="p">:</span>            <span class="nx">messageJson</span><span class="p">,</span>
</span><span class='line'>      <span class="nx">DeliveryMode</span><span class="p">:</span>    <span class="nx">amqp</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">Transient</span><span class="p">,</span>
</span><span class='line'>      <span class="nx">Priority</span><span class="p">:</span>        <span class="mi">0</span><span class="p">,</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="p">},</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="p">)</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="k">select</span> <span class="p">{</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="k">case</span> <span class="nx">tag</span> <span class="o">:=</span> <span class="o">&lt;-</span><span class="nx">ack</span><span class="p">:</span>
</span><span class='line'>      <span class="nx">log</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">Println</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="s">&quot;Acked &quot;</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="nx">tag</span><span class="p">)</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="k">case</span> <span class="nx">tag</span> <span class="o">:=</span> <span class="o">&lt;-</span><span class="nx">nack</span><span class="p">:</span>
</span><span class='line'>      <span class="nx">log</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">Println</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="s">&quot;Nack alert! &quot;</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="nx">tag</span><span class="p">)</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="p">}</span>
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>After each publish, I&rsquo;m performing a read off of the <code>ack</code> and <code>nack</code> chans (that is what <code>select</code> does). That read blocks until the client gets an ACK or NACK back from the broker.</p>

<p>The above examples are in Go, but there&rsquo;s an equivalent in the other libraries I&rsquo;ve played with. Clojure (langohr) has <code>confirm/select</code> and <code>confirm/wait-for-confirms-or-die</code>.</p>

<h3>Can we do better?</h3>

<p>Yes. Rather than wait for an ACK after each publish, it&rsquo;s better to publish a bunch of messages, listen for ACKs, and then handle failures. I didn&rsquo;t, because I was already seeing performance several orders of magnitude better than I needed.</p>

<p>We can also wrap blocks of messages in a transaction if we need to ensure that all messages get published and retain order, but doing that incurs something like a 250x performance penalty.</p>

<h2>Pool your Goroutines and avoid race conditions</h2>

<p><a href="https://github.com/streadway/amqp/issues/93">This issue</a> proved interesting (if ultimately not relevant to my problem). It looks like the person who filed the issue was running into two issues:</p>

<ul>
<li>There was a race condition in the code that counted ACKs / NACKs</li>
<li>The one-Goroutine-per-publish strategy causes a condition where the 2000 goroutines waiting for network IO prevent the goroutine listening for ACKs / NACKs from receiving sufficient CPU cycles.</li>
</ul>


<p>I got around this in two ways: I have a fixed-size pool of Goroutines performing the publishing, and each goroutine handles its own Publish &ndash;> Ack lifecycle.</p>

<h2>Ensuring messages get handled correctly</h2>

<p>A message queue is of little use if messages just sit there, so it is prudent to include a consumer or two. But, what happens if your consumer crashes? Does your message get lost in the ether?</p>

<p>The answer is <strong>AutoAck</strong>. More specifically, realizing that AutoAck is dangerous and wrong.</p>

<p>When a consumer consumes a message from a queue, the queue broker waits for an ACK before discarding the message. When a consumer has AutoAck enabled, it sends the ACK (thus causing the message to be discarded) instantly upon receiving the message. It&rsquo;s smarter to read the next message on the queue, handle the message properly, and then send the ACK.</p>

<figure class='code'><figcaption><span>Reading and acknowledging messages</span></figcaption><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
<span class='line-number'>6</span>
<span class='line-number'>7</span>
<span class='line-number'>8</span>
<span class='line-number'>9</span>
<span class='line-number'>10</span>
<span class='line-number'>11</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='go'><span class='line'><span class="nx">autoAck</span> <span class="o">:=</span> <span class="kc">false</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'><span class="nx">msgs</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="nx">err</span> <span class="o">:=</span> <span class="nx">channel</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">Consume</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="nx">q</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">Name</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="s">&quot;&quot;</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="nx">autoAck</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="kc">false</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="kc">false</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="kc">false</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="kc">nil</span><span class="p">)</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="k">if</span> <span class="nx">err</span> <span class="o">!=</span> <span class="kc">nil</span> <span class="p">{</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="nb">panic</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="nx">err</span><span class="p">)</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="p">}</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'><span class="k">for</span> <span class="nx">d</span> <span class="o">:=</span> <span class="k">range</span> <span class="nx">msgs</span> <span class="p">{</span> <span class="c1">// the d stands for Delivery</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="nx">log</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">Printf</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="nb">string</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="nx">d</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">Body</span><span class="p">[:]))</span> <span class="c1">// or whatever you want to do with the message</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="nx">d</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">Ack</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="kc">false</span><span class="p">)</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="p">}</span>
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>In the example above, <code>autoAck</code> is set to false. Every time I read a message (in the <code>for d := range msgs</code> loop), I send an ACK for that message. If I were to call <code>d.Ack(true)</code>, that would send an ACK for that message and all previous unacknowledged messages.</p>

<p>If my consumer quits without acknowledging a message, that message is repeated to the next consumer to come by.</p>

<h2>Performant results</h2>

<p>So, what kind of performance am I getting?</p>

<p>The following numbers are all time to publish and consume 100,000 messages, each with a 10KB payload. The tester was running on my Macbook, and RabbitMQ was running on a Cloudstack VM.</p>

<ul>
<li>With Confirm Select

<ul>
<li>Publishing: 24.42s</li>
<li>Consuming: 26.79s</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Without Confirm Select

<ul>
<li>Publishing: 16.32s</li>
<li>Consuming: 26.13s</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<p>The point is, RabbitMQ is fast and Go is fast. When we use one to stress test the other, messages get lost somewhere. If we take a little bit of time to ensure that messages get published and processed properly, we can prevent pesky data loss issues.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Joke]]></title>
    <link href="http://agocs.org/blog/2014/08/16/the-joke/"/>
    <updated>2014-08-16T17:47:53-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://agocs.org/blog/2014/08/16/the-joke</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Last night, I had a dream that I was telling a joke. It was a long one. I got almost all the way to the punchline before I woke up, and, thinking back on it, I had completely botched the setup. Shame on me.</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s the joke:</p>

<p>In eastern Europe, some time in the 15th century, there was a young rabbi. He was just out of training and was not ready to settle down, so he was wandering the countryside performing good deeds.</p>

<p>One day in late spring, the rabbi came across a village situated at the base of a tall mountain. In Roman times, the village was called Villi de Trido, but the villagers just called it Trid and, each other, Trids. The rabbi stayed at the inn one night, and noticed that the Trids looked unusually malnourished and depressed. He took the innkeeper aside and inquired as to what was going on.</p>

<p>&ldquo;There is a rare and special fruit that only grows on the southern face of the mountain that towers above Trid. We Trids used to harvest the fruit. It nourshed us, and we would trade with neighboring villages, and Trid was prosperous! But last year, a monster inhabited the southern face of the mountain. When we go up to pick the delicate fruits, he kicks us off the mountain! Pow, just like that! Now we starve, and we cannot trade with the neighboring villages.&rdquo;</p>

<p>The rabbi could not let this go. He promised the innkeeper he would do something about it. Perhaps he could talk the monster into a deal with the villagers. He bought a stout rope, a pair of warm gloves, and borrowed some crampons to deal with ice. The next morning, he started up the mountain.</p>

<p>He climbed for hours, expecting to encounter the monster at every turn. The rabbi seemed brave, but he was honestly nervous. What do you say to a monster? He climbed higher and higher, dealing with more and more snow and ice, wishing he had borrowed a heavy coat. As the light faded and he was about to consider making camp for the night, he encountered the grove where the fruit grew! The trees were majestic, and he could see even now the first little fruits starting to bud.</p>

<p>He heard a noise behind him, and wheeled around to find the monster! It stood twelve feet tall, with shaggy black fur and massive paws the size of a man&rsquo;s face. Fearsome though it was, the monster didn&rsquo;t attack. The rabbi waited a moment, and then decided to speak. &ldquo;Monster! The people of the village below say that you kick them off of the mountain. Why is it you have not kicked <em>me</em> from the mountain?&rdquo;</p>

<p>The monster approached the rabbi, and extended one gigantic paw. Placing it on the man&rsquo;s shoulder, the monster said, &ldquo;Silly rabbi. Kicks are for Trids!&rdquo;</p>

<hr />

<p>In my dream, I made the mistake of calling the fruit &ldquo;Trids&rdquo; rather than the villagers. I&rsquo;m glad I woke up. That would have been <em>embarassing!</em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Arduino Workshop]]></title>
    <link href="http://agocs.org/blog/2014/06/26/arduino-workshop/"/>
    <updated>2014-06-26T09:33:30-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://agocs.org/blog/2014/06/26/arduino-workshop</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Sometimes, shit doesn&rsquo;t work out. For example: Mike&rsquo;s Hard Lemonade contacted me at the <a href="http://sshchicago.org">Southside Hackerspace</a>, wanting us to modify a golf cart as part of their &ldquo;Mike&rsquo;s Hacks&rdquo; summer ad campaign. I dumped a lot of time (and just a little money) into the project, but everything went south at the last minute.</p>

<p>But this isn&rsquo;t about that.</p>

<p>At the same time, <a href="http://www.pinterest.com/r4v5/">Mason Donahue</a> put me in touch with <a href="https://www.facebook.com/ChicagoGirlsInComputing">Chicago Girls in Computing</a>. I put together a lesson plan, put together Arduino kits, made a powerpoint, and taught a class. It went awesome.</p>

<p>I had them assemble and program basic nightlights (LEDs turn on when the ambient light drops). They took that idea and ran with it.</p>

<p>The kits:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00761NDHI/ref=oh_details_o01_s00_i00?ie=UTF8&amp;psc=1">Sainsmart Nano V3</a> &mdash; $14</li>
<li><a href="https://www.adafruit.com/products/64">Half-size breadboard</a> &mdash; $5</li>
<li><a href="https://www.adafruit.com/products/161">Photoresistor</a> &mdash; $1</li>
<li>10Kohm resistor</li>
<li>9v battery</li>
<li>9v battery leads</li>
<li>bunches of LEDs</li>
</ul>


<p>The total cost per student came out to about $27. I was able to pick up a bunch of plastic containers from the grocery store for $0.10 each, and the kits fit into the containers.</p>

<iframe src="http://www.slideshare.net/slideshow/embed_code/36339800" width="476" height="400" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe>


<p>They seemed to like it.</p>

<p><a href="http://agocs.smugmug.com/Other/misc/29939745_7n8ptc#!i=3343759361&k=5fwQCB6&lb=1&s=A" title="Photo & Video Sharing by SmugMug"><img src="http://agocs.smugmug.com/Other/misc/i-5fwQCB6/0/L/20140621151638-L.jpg" title="Photo & Video Sharing by SmugMug" alt="Photo & Video Sharing by SmugMug"></a></p>

<p><a href="http://agocs.smugmug.com/Other/misc/29939745_7n8ptc#!i=3343759349&k=hKHRThm&lb=1&s=A" title="Photo & Video Sharing by SmugMug"><img src="http://agocs.smugmug.com/Other/misc/i-hKHRThm/0/L/20140621151700-L.jpg" title="Photo & Video Sharing by SmugMug" alt="Photo & Video Sharing by SmugMug"></a></p>

<p><a href="http://agocs.smugmug.com/Other/misc/29939745_7n8ptc#!i=3343759469&k=3W5HDLF&lb=1&s=A" title=""><img src="http://agocs.smugmug.com/Other/misc/i-3W5HDLF/0/L/20140621151538-L.jpg" title="" alt=""></a></p>

<p><a href="http://agocs.smugmug.com/Other/misc/29939745_7n8ptc#!i=3343759220&k=9WTNCvh&lb=1&s=A" title=""><img src="http://agocs.smugmug.com/Other/misc/i-9WTNCvh/0/L/20140621151415-L.jpg" title="" alt=""></a></p>

<p>Major props go to Backstop, Stack Overflow, and DigitalOcean. I wrote them at the last minute saying it would sure be neat if I could give out some stickers at the workshop. Backstop gave me pads and pens, Stack Overflow sent stickers and markers, and DigitalOcean sent me a bunch of stickers (and chocolates).</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Robot Finds Kitten as a Service]]></title>
    <link href="http://agocs.org/blog/2014/04/24/robot-finds-kitten-as-a-service/"/>
    <updated>2014-04-24T16:12:37-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://agocs.org/blog/2014/04/24/robot-finds-kitten-as-a-service</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I put together a webservice that serves 700 items that are not kittens.</p>

<p><a href="https://github.com/agocs/RobotFindsKittenServer">Github link</a></p>

<p><a href="http://agocs.org/robotfindskitten/non-kitten-item/">Watch it go</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Server Migration]]></title>
    <link href="http://agocs.org/blog/2014/04/15/migration/"/>
    <updated>2014-04-15T16:53:19-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://agocs.org/blog/2014/04/15/migration</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I know my site doesn&rsquo;t exactly have any dedicated watchers, but if anyone noticed a period of downtime earlier this week, it&rsquo;s because I was migrating from hosting on FatCow to hosting on a rented VPS through DigitalOcean. I also moved my domain registration from FatCow to Gandi.net. In this post, I plan to cover the hows, whys, and some lessons learned.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;ll start with the juicy stuff.</p>

<h1>Why?</h1>

<p>There are a couple of reasons, but the root of it all is that I got fed up with FatCow. It&rsquo;s not clear how their pricing <strike>varies</strike> increases from year to year, and it&rsquo;s obnoxious how, every few months, I find myself signed up for another &ldquo;free trial&rdquo; of some service out of which I have to opt. I can roll my own solution for less money, and with greater control.</p>

<h2>Why move away from FatCow?</h2>

<p>Like I said above, money and annoyance. I have a few sites with FatCow, and the oldest is about to round the three year mark. When I signed up, I was offered a trial rate of around $30 for the first year. That&rsquo;s a very good deal. I barely used the site, but I ignored a few emails and, lo and behold, I found myself renewed automatically to the tune of $70-something. Okay, that&rsquo;s still not significantly more than $5/month. Pretty darn good for unlimited hosting, the fact that I&rsquo;m not using it notwithstanding. I turned off automatic renewal.</p>

<p>A few months ago, I got a message saying that FatCow couldn&rsquo;t automatically renew that site because the card information I had stored was bad. I logged in, turned automatic renewal off again, and looked at the invoice &mdash; they were about to bill me $200-something for April 2014-April 2015! No way! That&rsquo;s way too much.</p>

<p>I just renewed Agocs.org to the tune of $70-something with FatCow, but I decided it was in my best interests to break ties with that company completely, something I will be doing over the next few weeks.</p>

<h2>Why Gandi.net?</h2>

<p>Bluntly, they have a &ldquo;no bullshit&rdquo; policy. That, and they were recommended by a trusted coworker and friend, and they are a French corporation and French law meaningfully allows them to transfer ownership of &ldquo;Agocs.org&rdquo; over to me (most American registrars, I have been informed, retain ownership of the domain name and license its usage to you).</p>

<p>The process of getting things set up with Gandi.net was a little rocky, as I will detail below, but they have a bunch of good help text and an extensive knowledge base. I was able to get up and running quickly and with minimal bugging of my more knowledgeable friends.</p>

<h2>Why DigitalOcean?</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve hosted a few VPSs with DigitalOcean before, and they are a joy to work with. I get full control of a Linux box (something I never got from FatCow), I can choose my web server (Nginx all the way) and database back-end (none for me please!), and set it up however I want. Write a script that uses rsync to publish new articles? Sure! Go nuts! I fought with FatCow for a while about that, and resorted to using FTP (which, once you&rsquo;ve started using rsync, sucks).</p>

<p>Anyway, one small VPS costs me about five bones per month. Because I&rsquo;m just the tiniest bit clever, I can host several sites on the same VPS. They&rsquo;re all static content generated by Octopress, so it&rsquo;s not like I&rsquo;m going to outgrow the small server any time soon. It&rsquo;s <em>really</em> nice.</p>

<h1>How it worked</h1>

<p>The process was straightforward. I set up the VPS with DigitalOcean first, copied my site over there, installed Nginx, and got that configured. Then I requested a transfer code from FatCow (I suspect, but cannot confirm, that they drag their feet on this), and initiated the transfer through Gandi. The transfer cost me about $13, but that means Agocs.org is mine for an additional year. When the transfer was complete, I created a DNS Zone file through Gandi&rsquo;s web interface that points to my VPS.</p>

<h1>Lessons learned</h1>

<p>I made my fair share of mistakes, mostly in setting up the DNS Zonefile. My first attempt looked like this:</p>

<pre><code>* 10800 IN A 162.243.76.63
</code></pre>

<p>www.agocs.org worked great, but no email and no plain ol&#8217; agocs.org. Email was more critical, so around midnight that night I changed it to this:</p>

<pre><code>* 10800 IN A 162.243.76.63
imap 10800 IN CNAME access.mail.gandi.net.
pop 10800 IN CNAME access.mail.gandi.net.
smtp 10800 IN CNAME relay.mail.gandi.net.
@ 10800 IN MX 50 fb.mail.gandi.net.
@ 10800 IN MX 10 spool.mail.gandi.net.
</code></pre>

<p>The lines below were cribbed from Gandi.net&rsquo;s default Zone file. <a href="&#109;&#x61;&#105;&#108;&#116;&#x6f;&#x3a;&#x63;&#104;&#x72;&#x69;&#115;&#64;&#97;&#103;&#111;&#x63;&#x73;&#x2e;&#x6f;&#x72;&#x67;">&#99;&#x68;&#x72;&#x69;&#115;&#x40;&#x61;&#103;&#111;&#x63;&#x73;&#46;&#x6f;&#114;&#103;</a> worked, but agocs.org did not. I did some research and then made the following change:</p>

<pre><code>* 10800 IN A 162.243.76.63
@ 10800 IN A 162.243.76.63
imap 10800 IN CNAME access.mail.gandi.net.
pop 10800 IN CNAME access.mail.gandi.net.
smtp 10800 IN CNAME relay.mail.gandi.net.
@ 10800 IN MX 50 fb.mail.gandi.net.
@ 10800 IN MX 10 spool.mail.gandi.net.
</code></pre>

<p>I found out the * record points all _sub_domains to that IP address, but it does not point the root domain (i.e. agocs.org) there. The @ record points the root domain to that IP address.</p>

<p>Finally, I noticed a problem with sent email. The last change I had to make was through Gmail, which was sending agocs.org traffic through an SMTP server run by FatCow. I&rsquo;m way too lazy to roll my own SMTP server, so I told Gmail to take care of it.</p>

<p>There you have it.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Someone stole the T]]></title>
    <link href="http://agocs.org/blog/2014/03/18/someone-stole-the-t/"/>
    <updated>2014-03-18T13:17:14-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://agocs.org/blog/2014/03/18/someone-stole-the-t</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Hoooooly shit! Somebody did it! Somebody stole the T!</p>

<p><a href="http://agocs.smugmug.com/Other/misc/29939745_7n8ptc#!i=3129590478&k=9sKRVBF&lb=1&s=A" title="Photo & Video Sharing by SmugMug"><img src="http://agocs.smugmug.com/Other/misc/i-9sKRVBF/0/L/Ech-L.jpg" title="Photo & Video Sharing by SmugMug" alt="Photo & Video Sharing by SmugMug"></a></p>

<p>Haha, awesome!</p>

<p><a href="http://agocs.smugmug.com/Other/misc/29939745_7n8ptc#!i=3129921045&k=c3jWCmv&lb=1&s=A" title="Photo & Video Sharing by SmugMug"><img src="http://agocs.smugmug.com/Other/misc/i-c3jWCmv/0/L/Ech3-L.jpg" title="Photo & Video Sharing by SmugMug" alt="Photo & Video Sharing by SmugMug"></a></p>

<p>Whoever did this, bravo! Bra-vo! I hope they let you graduate.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Intro to Golang]]></title>
    <link href="http://agocs.org/blog/2014/03/16/intro-to-golang-presentation/"/>
    <updated>2014-03-16T15:15:39-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://agocs.org/blog/2014/03/16/intro-to-golang-presentation</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Hey everybody, check out this intro to the Go programming language I put together for a talk at Backstop the other week!</p>

<p><a href="http://go-talks.appspot.com/github.com/agocs/GolangIntro/golangIntro.slide#1">Golang Slides</a></p>

<p>I tried to keep the slides content-light, since I find that having too many things on the screen distracts from what I&rsquo;m saying. I&rsquo;ll recapitulate my notes below.</p>

<ol>
<li>Title slide. Blah blah blah.</li>
<li><ul>
<li><p><strong>Around since 2009</strong>
Go started as a research project at Google in 2007. It was released as an open source project in 2009, and Go 1.0 dropped in March of 2012. It&rsquo;s a real-live language!</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Static Typing</strong>
Kinda &mdash;> Go uses Type Inference, but variables are statically typed once the type has been inferred. This is a reaction to the popularity of languages like JavaScript and Python, and gets away from the &ldquo;cumbersome type systems&rdquo; used in the C family and Java.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Object Oriented</strong>
Kinda &mdash;> Go is object oriented, but it doesn&rsquo;t have classes. I&rsquo;ll get into this later.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Garbage Collected</strong>
Yes.</p></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><p>What is it good at? Some of the notable features are quick compile times (which it achieves through clean dependency analysis and no wasted imports or declarations), creation of statically linked binaries, and concurrency, which I dive into later.</p></li>
<li><p>Why Go?</p>

<ul>
<li><p><strong>Systems Programming</strong> Go represents a next big step in systems programming. Systems programming is the creation of OSes, utilities, drivers, and so-forth. It has to be fast, resource-conscious, and rock solid. C has been the big name in systems programming, but that came out in 1972. C++ came out in 79, and since there, what has there been? D? PL/8? Go and Mozilla Rust are the two up and coming names in systems programming for this century.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Multicore Computers</strong> Moore&rsquo;s law no longer applies. We&rsquo;re making computers faster by cramming more and more cores onto a processor and more and more processors onto a motherboard. If you look at concurrency support in C or Java or any other enterprise language, it&rsquo;s all abysmal. Go has primitives for concurrency built in. It&rsquo;s so beautiful, it&rsquo;s crazy.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Make Programming Fun</strong> I think so, at least. At the end of the talk, we wrote a little application that measures response time to a handful of websites and screwed around with it for a while. Not to toot my own horn, but a fellow dev told me it was &ldquo;one of the best live coding exercises he had ever seen.&rdquo;</p></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><p><strong>Hello World</strong> Nothing special here. &lsquo;fmt&rsquo; is the formatting package in Go&rsquo;s standard library, much like Stdio.h.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Basic syntax</strong> What I wanted to call out here is the difference between Go&rsquo;s function declaration syntax and that in the C family. C-style declaration is really focused on what a variable / function evaluates to, while Go is more focused on what the thing <em>is</em>. I talked a little bit about the Clockwise-Spiral rule.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Static Typing and Type Inference</strong> I talked about how you declare variables. <code>myName</code> is in the global address space, while <code>myAge</code> is local to the <code>main</code> method. Some key points:</p>

<ul>
<li><p><code>myAge := 26</code> &mdash; <code>:=</code> is a shorthand form of declaration and assignment that only works in the local scope. Here, Go&rsquo;s type inference is assuming that I want <code>myAge</code> to be an int.</p></li>
<li><p><code>var myAge = 26</code> is just a longhand version of the above.</p></li>
<li><p><code>var myAge int64 = 26</code> &mdash; Let&rsquo;s say we live in a world where people live a very long time. Here, I&rsquo;m overriding Go&rsquo;s type inference and telling Go that <code>myAge</code> will be a 64 bit int.</p></li>
<li><p><code>myAge := 28 / myAge= := 26</code> Let&rsquo;s say I made a mistake and went to reassign 26 to <code>myAge</code>. I can&rsquo;t do it this way; the compiler says &ldquo;You already declared <code>myAge</code>, dumbass.&rdquo; If you erase the <code>:</code> on the  second line, you can reassign <code>myAge</code>.</p></li>
<li><p><code>myBrother := "Rob"</code> &mdash; We can&rsquo;t declare a variable without using it. It throws a compiler error. This is part of how Go keeps compile times down.</p></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><p>Object Orientation &mdash; Here&rsquo;s a quick example of how Go is object oriented. We&rsquo;re declaring a struct called littleBox that holds a couple of ints. We can create a litteBox and use it.</p></li>
<li><p>More Object Orientation &mdash; Here, we&rsquo;re declaring a littleBox and a bigBox that holds a littleBox. The function</p>

<p> <pre>func (bb bigBox) makeString() string {
     return fmt.Sprintf(&ldquo;contains %d books and %d baseball cards&rdquo;, bb.numBooks, bb.little.numBaseballCards)
 }</pre></p>

<p> creates a function on bigBox that makes it into a string. This is how Go is object oriented, but eschews classes. Whats <em>neat</em> is, if you change <code>func (bb bigBox) makeString()</code> into <code>func (bb bigBox) String()</code>, and change <code>fmt.Println(myBigBox.makeString())</code> into <code>fmt.Println(myBigBox)</code>, you&rsquo;ve made bigBox <em>implement</em> the Stringer interface! Did you explicitly do this? No! But you did it anyway! Isn&rsquo;t that awesome?</p></li>
<li><p>Compile times are quick. I wish I had a really big example to show you, but suffice to say that, every time you click &ldquo;Run&rdquo; on the presentation, the code is being sent back to the server, compiled, run, and the result is sent back to you.</p></li>
<li><p>Go compiles to native binaries. To demonstrate this, I opened iTerm, ran <code>go build hello_world.go</code>, then ran <code>file hello_world</code> to demonstrate that <code>hello_world</code> had compiled to a binary. Then I moved <code>hello_world</code> to <code>/opt/local/bin</code> and ran <code>hello_world</code>, which, of course, output:</p>

<p><pre>
cagocs:~ christopheragocs$ hello_world
Hello, world!
</pre></p></li>
<li><p>Go comes with a number of primitives to handle concurrency. They are:</p>

<ul>
<li><p><strong>Goroutines</strong> &mdash; you can think of these as being super light, cheap threads. What really happens is a new stack frame is created in the same address space as the parent, and concurrent goroutines are multiplexed using threads. All of the actual thread juggling is handled behind the scenes.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Channels</strong> &mdash; these are concurrency-safe buffers used for communication between goroutines.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Select</strong> &mdash; selects between receiving channels.</p></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><p>Here&rsquo;s a purposefully slow example. <code>aBigNumber</code> calls a naive recursive implementation of the Fibonacci function, which delays execution for a few seconds. <code>aSmallNumber</code> either never gets a chance to execute, or executes much later.</p></li>
<li><p>In this one, we&rsquo;ve created a channel called <code>results</code>. We&rsquo;ve prefixed the calls to <code>aSmallNumber()</code> and <code>aBigNumber()</code> with the <code>go</code> keyword, which tells Go to execute them in separate goroutines. Both functions put the result onto the <code>results</code> channel, and the main method reads the results off of the channel in that order. In this instance, it will print &ldquo;7&rdquo; first, and then whatever the huge fib(42) is (or else execution on the remote server will time out first).</p></li>
<li><p>This was the programming exercise. You can look at the code on Github. In short, it accesses 24 different websites concurrently, and prints out the site, the access time, and the status code in order of completion. I wrote this with a really great group of developers, and we went off on a number of tangents trying different things to figure out some deep implementation details of Go (which explains the <code>time.Sleep(1000000000)</code> on line 30.</p></li>
</ol>


<p>I used the &ldquo;Present&rdquo; tool, which is part of the Golang tool kit. I enjoyed using it, as it lets you use code examples pretty heavily, and the code examples can be modified in-browser and executed live. When I posted the talk on Facebook, an old professor of mine asked me about that, which I thought was pretty cool.</p>

<p>Giving the talk to the developers I work with was a lot of fun. Backstop Solutions employs a bunch of really smart people, and it&rsquo;s a pleasure when they ask deep probing questions that go beyond your knowledge. A++++, 10 stars, would present again.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cold brew coffee: try # 1]]></title>
    <link href="http://agocs.org/blog/2013/09/10/cold-brew-coffee-try-1/"/>
    <updated>2013-09-10T22:34:15-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://agocs.org/blog/2013/09/10/cold-brew-coffee-try-1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I saw a Kickstarter for a <a href="http://www.kickstarter.com/projects/bruer/cold-bruer-a-cold-brew-coffee-system?ref=recently_launched">cold brew coffee device</a> today, and I started reading about it. Cold Brew is supposed to taste different from your traditional hot brews &mdash; it gets less of the acidic flavors than traditionally brewed coffee, so you wind up with a smoother beverage. Also, cold brew techniques produce a coffee concentrate that you&rsquo;re supposed to dilute, and the idea of mixing up 50/50 cold brew and milk is interesting.</p>

<p>I had a Twitter exchange with my friend <a href="http://www.killpack.biz/resume.html">Jordan Killpack</a> about cold brewin&#8217;, and we determined that the Kickstarter device, while nicely engineered, was a little highfalutin. I decided to try my own cold brew using nothing but mason jars and coffee filters (and coffee, and water).</p>

<h3>Ingredients</h3>

<ul>
<li><p>Starbucks Blonde Roast, pre-ground (don&rsquo;t judge, it was on sale and all the good coffee places were closed at this point)</p></li>
<li><p>Two one-cup Mason jars with canning lids</p></li>
<li><p>Two standard paper coffee filters</p></li>
<li><p>Water</p></li>
</ul>


<p>Going off of the <a href="http://www.americastestkitchenfeed.com/recipes/homemade-cold-brew-coffee/">America&rsquo;s Test Kitchen recipe</a>, I put 60g coffee in the mason jar and added 240g water. After a few minutes, I stirred. I&rsquo;m going to let it sit until tomorrow night, and then I&rsquo;ll try it out.</p>

<h3>Pictures:</h3>

<p><a href="http://agocs.smugmug.com/Other/misc/29939745_7n8ptc#!i=2758217838&amp;k=6BZpvCS&amp;lb=1&amp;s=A"><img src="http://agocs.smugmug.com/Other/misc/i-6BZpvCS/0/L/20130910_215129-L.jpg" alt="Photo &amp; Video Sharing by SmugMug" /></a></p>

<p>On the right is coffee + water that&rsquo;s been sitting for about 10 minutes. I just finished stirring the one on the left.</p>

<p><a href="http://agocs.smugmug.com/Other/misc/29939745_7n8ptc#!i=2758217643&amp;k=99wChNd&amp;lb=1&amp;s=A"><img src="http://agocs.smugmug.com/Other/misc/i-99wChNd/0/L/20130910_215215-L.jpg" alt="" /></a></p>

<p>On the right is the prototype for how I&rsquo;m going to filter the coffee tomorrow. I&rsquo;ll just invert the assembly over a bowl or big cup and let it all drain. I&rsquo;ll update with how it worked out.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Moving: a post-mortem]]></title>
    <link href="http://agocs.org/blog/2013/08/09/moving-a-post-mortem/"/>
    <updated>2013-08-09T23:34:48-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://agocs.org/blog/2013/08/09/moving-a-post-mortem</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Last month, I moved from Atlanta to Chicago. Moving always sucks; that&rsquo;s a universal constant*, but I think this one went better than most. I&rsquo;ve compiled a list of what worked and what didn&rsquo;t, and some notes on what to do better next time.</p>

<h2>What Worked</h2>

<h4>Trello</h4>

<p>Sabrina and I planned the move and tracked our tasks on Trello.com. I have to say, the ability to put together dynamic kanban-style task boards on the fly really helped us keep everything straight.</p>

<h4>Penske Trucks</h4>

<p>We rented a 26&#8221; straight truck from Penske for this move. That&rsquo;s a big truck, but I decided it&rsquo;s better to have more truck than you need. It cost me less than $500 renting from Saturday &ndash; Wednesday, but what I neglected to consider was, on a move of that distance, I would need around 100 gallons of diesel fuel (right around $300-400).</p>

<p>Another consideration is height &mdash; the truck was specified at 12&#8217;7&#8221;. That&rsquo;s short enough to clear most bridges, but I did come across one 12&#8217;6&#8221; bridge in downtown Chicago.</p>

<p>Bridges aside, the Penske truck was comfortable and easy to drive. The AC worked great, and the stereo had an Aux input for my phone. It turned about as expected (surprisingly tight for a 30 foot truck), but it accelerated reasonably quickly and cruised comfortably at 70. I was concerned about a mountain in Monteagle, TN, but the truck made it up the grade easily when I dropped down to 5th, and I was never concerned about a runaway on the way down (again, engine braking in 4th or 5th).</p>

<h4>Audible.com</h4>

<p>It&rsquo;s a long, long, long drive from Atlanta to Chicago. I made it better by listening to <em>A Supposedly Fun Thing I&rsquo;ll Never Do Again: Essays and Arguments </em>by David Foster Wallace, purchased through Audible. Audible made it really easy to pick an audiobook based on length (I didn&rsquo;t want to buy the 44 hour <em>Song of Ice and Fire</em>), and I actually turned to my Amazon recommendations for the book itself.</p>

<p>The first essay in <em>A Supposedly Fun Thing</em>, entitled &ldquo;Derivative Sport in Tornado Alley&rdquo;, is about DFW&rsquo;s childhood in rural Illinois. It was interesting hearing his thoughts on the Illinois geography through the eyes of a child athlete.</p>

<h4>Rent-A-Crate</h4>

<p>Cardboard boxes suck.</p>

<p>Let me rephrase that: Poorly assembled, poorly packed cardboard boxes suck. A properly assembled and packed cardboard box will bear (most of) the weight of the box(es) above it without destroying your stuff. An over-packed cardboard box means that the weight of the boxes above it is now being supported by your stuff, and when you&rsquo;re in frenzied packing mode, it&rsquo;s really easily to get sloppy in assembling and packing.</p>

<p>There&rsquo;s a company called Rent-A-Crate with offices in several major cities around the country. They&rsquo;ll rent you these big orange crates for $3.50/crate/10 day period. They&rsquo;re sturdy, they nest, they stack stably, and they kick ass. I discovered that 20 crates fit into the back of my station wagon &mdash; just. I rented 25, and wound up taking them back in batches of 15 and 10.</p>

<p>The only drawback (and some may see this as a positive) is that they force you to unpack your stuff, because you&rsquo;re paying for the crates otherwise.</p>

<h4>The Home Depot</h4>

<p>I used to live down the street from not one but two Home Depot stores. It was great being able to run to The Home Depot to pick up bubble wrap, tape, more boxes (caveat, see previous section), and even the big god damn truck.</p>

<h4>Waze</h4>

<p>I relied on Waze, a navigation app for my Android phone, to get me to Chicago. It&rsquo;s interesting because it dynamically rerouts you based on traffic, and it took me up US41, a rural highway that divides Indiana and Illinois, while Google took my girlfriend and her mother up I-65 through Indianapolis.</p>

<p>Right as the sun was setting, the lightning bugs over the fields to either side of US41 were a sight to see.</p>

<h4>Movers</h4>

<p>One thing I realized was that it would be a huge pain in the ass getting everything up and down stairs. We used Simple Moving Labor to hire movers in Atlanta and Chicago. These guys wrapped all of our furniture up securely and handled the heavy lifting and truck packing much better than we ever could have done. They were self-directed, and really knew their business They were around $350 on each end, but well worth the cost.</p>

<h2>What Didn&rsquo;t</h2>

<h4>Cardboard Boxes</h4>

<p>Like I said earlier, a poorly assembled, poorly packed cardboard box quickly becomes a mushy paper bag with broken crap inside that you eventually have to dispose of. Guess what we had a bunch of!</p>

<h4>Moving the cats</h4>

<p>A few days before the move, I went to the pet supply store and picked up a big kennel on clearance. Sabrina went to the vet, and was given Xanax (seriously, human Xanax in human doses). We dosed the cats the morning of, and they liked it at first. Abby sat in the window, purring to herself, and Panther was jumping around swatting at things that weren&rsquo;t there. When we put them in the car, however, they haaaated it so bad. Sabrina said that they were meowing non-stop, and at one point they actually started to fight. Maybe we&rsquo;ll try some sort of sedative next time.</p>

<p>Having too much stuff</p>

<p>Seriously. I have no place for a telescope in Chicago! I should have started selling things months before.</p>

<h4>Moving my car</h4>

<p>Sabrina&rsquo;s Mom can drive a stick shift, so she drove it up. I&rsquo;m not saying anything, but she might not be as good as the thinks she is. The car made it up in one piece, but I would have been a lot more comfortable if it had been moved professionally.</p>

<h2>What would I do differently?</h2>

<p>Well, thank goodness, I don&rsquo;t have to move for another four years at least. I&rsquo;m going to start saving now, and maybe, just maybe, we&rsquo;ll hire a full service moving company. Sabrina and I will just get on a plane (and, doubtless, arrive to a pair of unhappy cats).</p>

<p>*Seriously, the easiest move I ever had was the one where my house burned down.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to: disable capslock at the hardware level]]></title>
    <link href="http://agocs.org/blog/2013/07/21/how-to-disable-capslock-at-the-hardware-level/"/>
    <updated>2013-07-21T00:09:09-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://agocs.org/blog/2013/07/21/how-to-disable-capslock-at-the-hardware-level</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I hate capslock. It&rsquo;s a horrible, horrible key, and it gets even more in the way on my split ergonomic keyboards at work. I&rsquo;ve tried registry hacks to kill it, but they don&rsquo;t seem to work. Here&rsquo;s how I deal with capslock:</p>

<ol>
<li> Obtain a small, flat-headed screwdriver. Insert it beneath the Capslock key.
[<img src="http://www.agocs.org/wp-content/uploads/2013/07/20130719_1104211-300x168.jpg" alt="20130719_110421[1]" /></li>
</ol>


<p>](<a href="http://www.agocs.org/wp-content/uploads/2013/07/20130719_1104211.jpg">http://www.agocs.org/wp-content/uploads/2013/07/20130719_1104211.jpg</a>)</p>

<ol>
<li> Pry downward.
<a href="http://www.agocs.org/wp-content/uploads/2013/07/20130719_1104371.jpg"><img src="http://www.agocs.org/wp-content/uploads/2013/07/20130719_1104371-300x168.jpg" alt="20130719_110437[1]" /></a></li>
</ol>


<p>If you ever need capslock later, just use a pen to poke the little capacitive sensor. I put the key into a drawer in case I ever need to reassemble the keyboard later.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Reverse Engineering Doubleclick Part II]]></title>
    <link href="http://agocs.org/blog/2013/05/17/reverse-engineering-doubleclick-part-ii/"/>
    <updated>2013-05-17T10:27:30-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://agocs.org/blog/2013/05/17/reverse-engineering-doubleclick-part-ii</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Once every three seconds, that&rsquo;s the magic number.</p>

<p>Some more interesting information: I pointed a Doubleclick click counter at a super-simple web service I wrote, running on a web server I rent, and I ran a test that follows the DLCK redirect. Here are the results:</p>

<p><a href="http://www.agocs.org/wp-content/uploads/2013/05/Delay_Between_Requests.png"><img src="http://www.agocs.org/wp-content/uploads/2013/05/Delay_Between_Requests-300x113.png" alt="Delay_Between_Requests" /></a></p>

<p>I ran 300 clicks at 4s per click, then 500 clicks at 2s per click. As you can see, almost all of the first 300 clicks made it to the web service, but only around 380/500 2s per click clicks made it. Here&rsquo;s the same graph with a log scale y axis:</p>

<p><a href="http://www.agocs.org/wp-content/uploads/2013/05/Delay_Between_Requests_log_scale.png"><img src="http://www.agocs.org/wp-content/uploads/2013/05/Delay_Between_Requests_log_scale-300x113.png" alt="Delay_Between_Requests_log_scale" /></a></p>

<p>You can see that the first 300 clicks made it with roughly 3 seconds between clicks (modulo some variance in the first 100 because I was using a gaussian random delay, and a hiccough at #100 because I stopped and restarted the test). The 380 clicks that made it at 2s per click mostly showed up in 2s intervals, but there were at least seven delays of greater than 10 seconds. In fact, I determined that if there was a delay of >4 seconds, it was almost certain that clicks received during this delay would not be delivered. This indicates to me that DLCK is actively watching for clickthrough rates of greater than a certain amount from a certain IP address, and dropping clicks.</p>

<p>Neat!</p>

<p>I tried spoofing DLCK cookies. I have yet to be successful.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Reverse Engineering Doubleclick Ad Statistics (Part 1)]]></title>
    <link href="http://agocs.org/blog/2013/05/07/reverse-engineering-doubleclick-ad-statistics-part-1/"/>
    <updated>2013-05-07T12:44:16-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://agocs.org/blog/2013/05/07/reverse-engineering-doubleclick-ad-statistics-part-1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>One of the projects I&rsquo;m on seeks to proxy web beacons. Basically, I have a WSGI app that serves a 1x1 px gif, and then triggers a Celery app that goes out and actually &ldquo;clicks&rdquo; on the intended web beacon. During preliminary load testing with a Doubleclick beacon (actually a Doubleclick link counter), we discovered that requesting that beacon 1000 times in 5 minutes (one request ever 1/3 second) only reported around 30 &ldquo;clicks.&rdquo; We&rsquo;ve been throwing tests at Doubleclick to see what it reports under different scenarios:</p>

<ul>
<li><p>1000 clicks evenly distributed over 5 minutes: 30 clicks</p></li>
<li><p>1000 clicks chunked into 50 groups of 20 (I misunderstood how JMeter works): 50 clicks</p></li>
<li><p>300 clicks over an hour (1 per 12 seconds): 300 clicks</p></li>
<li><p>500 clicks with spoofed User_agent strings (1 per 12 seconds): 500 clicks</p></li>
</ul>


<p>So it appears that Doubleclick has a &ldquo;cooldown&rdquo; between clicks and doesn&rsquo;t really care about the User_agent. How long is that cooldown? We know it&rsquo;s greater than 1/3 second and less than 12 seconds.</p>

<p>Today, I&rsquo;m running a test that looks like this:</p>

<p><strong>Number of clicks</strong></p>

<p><strong>Rate of clicks</strong></p>

<p><strong>Delay between clicks</strong></p>

<p><strong>Total time</strong></p>

<p>10240</p>

<p>240 per minute</p>

<p>.25 seconds</p>

<p>2560 s (42.6m)</p>

<p>5120</p>

<p>120 per minute</p>

<p>.5 seconds</p>

<p>2560 s (42.6m)</p>

<p>2560</p>

<p>80 per minute</p>

<p>.75 seconds</p>

<p>1920 s (32m)</p>

<p>1280</p>

<p>40 per minute</p>

<p>1.5 seconds</p>

<p>1920 s (32m)****</p>

<p>640</p>

<p>20 per minute</p>

<p>3 seconds</p>

<p>1920 s (32m)</p>

<p>320</p>

<p>10 per minute</p>

<p>6 seconds</p>

<p>1920 s (32m)</p>

<p>By taking the total number of clicks recorded today (which I&rsquo;ll know tomorrow), I&rsquo;ll be able to start approximating the cooldown (for example, if I see 2240 and change clicks, I&rsquo;ll know that the cooldown is between 1.5 and .75 seconds).</p>

<p>Will update later.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mergesort on all the spices in the kitchen]]></title>
    <link href="http://agocs.org/blog/2013/05/04/mergesort-spices/"/>
    <updated>2013-05-04T23:05:48-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://agocs.org/blog/2013/05/04/mergesort-spices</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It bothered me that the spices in the kitchen were out of order. So, I sorted them using my favorite sorting algorithm, Mergesort. My cats helped.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.agocs.org/wp-content/uploads/2013/05/2013-05-04_23-33-19_905.jpg"><img src="http://www.agocs.org/wp-content/uploads/2013/05/2013-05-04_23-33-19_905-300x168.jpg" alt="2013-05-04_23-33-19_905" /></a></p>

<p>I started with an un-ordered list of spices.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.agocs.org/wp-content/uploads/2013/05/2013-05-04_23-34-08_418.jpg"><img src="http://www.agocs.org/wp-content/uploads/2013/05/2013-05-04_23-34-08_418-300x168.jpg" alt="2013-05-04_23-34-08_418" /></a></p>

<p>Then I started to divide the list up into smaller lists. Panther helped.</p>

<p>31 elements became 15 and 16.</p>

<p>Then 7, 8, 8, 8.</p>

<p>Then 3, 4, 4, 4, 4, 4, 4, 4.</p>

<p>Then 1 2 2 2 2 2 2 2 2 2 2 2 2 2 2 2</p>

<p><a href="http://www.agocs.org/wp-content/uploads/2013/05/2013-05-04_23-35-32_948.jpg"><img src="http://www.agocs.org/wp-content/uploads/2013/05/2013-05-04_23-35-32_948-300x168.jpg" alt="2013-05-04_23-35-32_948" /></a></p>

<p>Then the sorting began. Each two element group, I sorted. Then I treated each one as a queue. For each set of two queues, I dequeued the head element of lowest alphabetical value, and enqueued it into a result queue. I repeated this until there was only one, sorted queue remaining.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.agocs.org/wp-content/uploads/2013/05/2013-05-04_23-46-38_85.jpg"><img src="http://www.agocs.org/wp-content/uploads/2013/05/2013-05-04_23-46-38_85-300x168.jpg" alt="2013-05-04_23-46-38_85" /></a></p>

<p>Then I put it back into the spice cabinet! When Sabrina asks, &ldquo;Who got my spices out of order,&rdquo; I will reply, &ldquo;I got them <em>in</em> order.&rdquo;</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to UrlEncode a String in C# using .Net 4.0 or less]]></title>
    <link href="http://agocs.org/blog/2013/04/23/how-to-urlencode-a-string-in-c-using-net-4-0-or-less/"/>
    <updated>2013-04-23T13:44:49-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://agocs.org/blog/2013/04/23/how-to-urlencode-a-string-in-c-using-net-4-0-or-less</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The boffins over at Microsoft added a handy method to .Net 4.5: <a href="http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/system.net.webutility.urlencode.aspx">Webutility.UrlEncode</a>. Unfortunately for those of us who don&rsquo;t have Visual Studio 2012, we can&rsquo;t use it! How then can we properly encode strings for use in URLs?</p>

<p>(What do I mean? Let&rsquo;s say I want to pass a URL inside another URL as an argument. So, for example, I want to pass <a href="http://www.bar.com/?a=b&amp;c=d%C2%A0_as">http://www.bar.com/?a=b&amp;c=d%C2%A0_as</a> a query string variable_ to foo.com. I&rsquo;d want the following URL: <a href="http://foo.com/?url=http%3A//www.bar.com/%3Fa%3Db%26c%3Dd">http://foo.com/?url=http%3A//www.bar.com/%3Fa%3Db%26c%3Dd</a>  )</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s how I did it:</p>

<p>I start by instantiating a StringBuilder with assumed length of 100 (I&rsquo;m not going to create a URL much longer than 100 characters, am I?). Then, for each character in the input URL, I call the replace(char c) function. Replace returns the string that the character <em>should</em> be, and that value gets appended to the StringBuilder. When we&rsquo;re done, the StringBuilder spits out the string.</p>

<p>I thought about doing an in-place replace, but that would have lead to a lot of shuffling within the string. My intuition told me the runtime would be somewhere along the lines of O(n<sup>2</sup>). I also thought about chaining a bunch of String.replace().replace().replace()&hellip; calls together, but that would have been a mess as well as a slow performer.</p>

<p>I wound up traded some space for time (yes, I am initializing a bunch of Strings), but I&rsquo;m effectively performing this encoding in O(n) time.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Box Fan Beef Jerky, part 2]]></title>
    <link href="http://agocs.org/blog/2013/04/22/box-fan-beef-jerky-part-2/"/>
    <updated>2013-04-22T21:19:20-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://agocs.org/blog/2013/04/22/box-fan-beef-jerky-part-2</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In <a href="http://www.agocs.org/box-fan-beef-jerky-part-1/">this post</a>, I started making box fan beef jerky. If you can&rsquo;t remember where I was when I left off, go take a peek.</p>

<p>Okay, so. The meat sat in the marinade overnight, and come morning I loaded it onto a 20&#8221; by 20&#8221; HVAC filter, courtesy of The Home Depot.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.agocs.org/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/2013-04-18_07-32-50_747.jpg"><img src="http://www.agocs.org/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/2013-04-18_07-32-50_747-300x168.jpg" alt="" /></a></p>

<p>The cats were very interested.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.agocs.org/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/2013-04-18_07-32-55_320.jpg"><img src="http://www.agocs.org/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/2013-04-18_07-32-55_320-300x168.jpg" alt="2013-04-18_07-32-55_320" /></a></p>

<p>I assembled the filters and strapped them to the fan.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.agocs.org/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/2013-04-18_19-22-01_231.jpg"><img src="http://www.agocs.org/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/2013-04-18_19-22-01_231-300x168.jpg" alt="2013-04-18_19-22-01_231" /></a></p>

<p>The cats were very interested.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.agocs.org/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/2013-04-18_07-37-39_570.jpg"><img src="http://www.agocs.org/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/2013-04-18_07-37-39_570-300x170.jpg" alt="2013-04-18_07-37-39_570" /></a></p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s what it looked like after a day at work:</p>

<p><a href="http://www.agocs.org/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/2013-04-18_22-29-49_87.jpg"><img src="http://www.agocs.org/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/2013-04-18_22-29-49_87-300x168.jpg" alt="2013-04-18_22-29-49_87" /></a></p>

<p>Tasty, but not properly preserved. I cut up the pieces too thick, originally. The above picture is after re-cutting, and before re-drying overnight.</p>

<p>I don&rsquo;t have any pictures of the next morning, but the results are good. The jerky had a nice, mellow flavor, and has kept in a tupperware on the counter over the course of the week. Sabrina put the bug in my head to make Sriracha beef jerky&hellip; guess what I&rsquo;m doing this weekend!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
